Guide to the Eleanor Clark Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Eleanor Clark papers
1881-1993
1933-1986
YCAL MSS 315
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
36.71
(53 boxes)
The Eleanor Clark Papers consists of writings, correspondence, and other materials documenting the life and work of the writer Eleanor Clark.
Clark, Eleanor, 1913-1996
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Eleanor Clark Papers was acquired through purchase and gifts. The bulk of the collection was acquired through purchase from Eleanor Clark in 1988. Additional materials were added to the collection through gifts from Eleanor Clark, in 1994 and 1996, and from Rosanna Warren, in 2005 and 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile papers in boxes 52-53 may be consulted only with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies or photographic prints for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
Existence and Location of Copies
Microfilm available through Access Services.
Eleanor Clark (1913-1996)
Eleanor Clark was the author of critically acclaimed novels and non-fictional works from the mid 1940s to mid 1980s, as well as short fiction, essays, poems, and plays. Novels included Bitter Box (1946), Baldur's Gate (1970), Gloria Mundi (1979), and Camping Out (1986). Non-fictional works included the travel narratives Rome and a Villa (1952) and Oysters of Locmariaquer (1965), which won the National Book Award, and the memoir Eyes, Etc. (1977).
Eleanor Clark was born July 6, 1913, in Los Angeles, California, raised in Roxbury, Connecticut, and educated at Vassar. She worked as a freelance writer, editor, and translator in the mid 1930s and as an editor for W.W. Norton & Company in New York from 1936 to 1939. Clark married Robert Penn Warren on December 7, 1952.
Summary information on Eleanor Clark is available in the standard print and online biographical resources.
Scope and Contents
The Eleanor Clark Papers consists of writings, correspondence, and personal papers documenting the life and work of the writer Eleanor Clark. Writings include work spanning over fifty years, from short stories and poems written and published while Clark was a undergraduate at Vassar in the early 1930s to the late fiction and non-fiction of the 1980s. The writings feature notes, drafts, proofs, and printed materials relating to Clark's published works of fiction and non-fiction, from drafts of what would become Baldur's Gate, dating from the mid 1930s, to drafts of her last novel, Camping Out (1986). In addition, there are drafts and printed versions of numerous published and unpublished shorter works, including short stories, essays, poems, plays, speeches, readings, and book reviews.
Correspondence in the collection consists chiefly of incoming letters from family, friends, writers, editors and publishers, and educational and cultural institutions. Larger correspondence files may be found for Clark's husband, Robert Penn Warren, her mother, her two children, Gabriel and Rosanna Warren, and Louis MacNeice, Katherine Anne Porter, and Muriel Rukeyser, among others. Other noteworthy correspondents include authors W.H. Auden, Saul Bellow, Hermann Broch, Albert Camus, John Cheever, Robert Fitzgerald, Elsa Morante, Eudora Welty, Glenway Wescott, and Thornton Wilder. There are also files of correspondence, including fan mail and letters from publishers, relating to published works.
Other materials include college papers, journals, and notebooks.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series: I. Writings, 1915-1993. II. Correspondence, 1876-1988. III. Personal Papers, 1881-1988.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Novelists, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Oyster culture -- France; Locmariaquer (France) -- Description and travel; Locmariaquer (France) -- Social life and customs; Rome (Italy) -- Description and travel; Rome (Italy) -- Social life and customs; Sahara -- Description and travel; Authors; Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973; Broch, Hermann, 1886-1951; Camus, Albert, 1913-1960; Cheever, John, 1912-1982; Clark, Eleanor, 1913-1996; Fitzgerald, Robert, 1910-1985; MacNeice, Louis, 1907-1963; Morante, Elsa, approximately 1912-1985; Porter, Katherine Anne, 1890-1980; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-1980; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-1989; Warren, Rosanna, 1953-; Welty, Eudora, 1909-2001; Wescott, Glenway, 1901-1987; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975
- Writings, 1915-1993; Series I; 10.63; (26 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Writings is organized into two subseries: Writings of Eleanor Clark and Writings of Others.
  The Writings of Eleanor Clark, housed in boxes 1-25, is subdivided for Novels, Non-Fiction, and Shorter Works, and arranged alphabetically by title within each subdivision. The writings feature notes, drafts, proofs, and printed materials relating to Clark's published works of fiction and non-fiction. There are, for example, drafts of what would become Baldur's Gate, dating from the mid 1930s, to drafts of her last novel, Camping Out, dating to 1986. In addition, there are drafts and printed versions of numerous published and unpublished shorter works, including short stories, essays, poems, plays, speeches, readings, and book reviews. Drafts for short stories published in the collection Dr. Heart are filed alphabetically in Shorter Works, whereas drafts for the collection, published by Pantheon Books in 1974, are filed in Novels. The titles to most shorter works are listed in quotes and printed versions are noted only when present; supplied titles are bracketed.
  Correspondence files relating to several of Clark's books have been preserved in Series II. Correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  The Writings of Others, housed in boxes 26-27, is arranged alphabetically and features drafts of poems and shorter works by John Pierrepont and Ethel P. Rice.
  - Writings of Eleanor Clark
    - Novels
      - Baldur's Gate
        - Drafts, [circa 1934] (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
        - Notes, 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - Notes and discards, 1966-1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 7-14)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 15-21)
        - Discards, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
        - Excerpts, 1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 23-25)
        - Publicity and reviews, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 26-29)
      - The Bitter Box
        - Draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 30-32)
        - Reviews, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Camping Out
        - Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
        - Draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 35-37)
        - Discards, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
        - Draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 39-41)
        - Discards, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 42)
        - Excerpt, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - Dr. Heart
        - Outline, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
        - Drafts, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 45-46)
        - Book jacket and designs, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 47)
          Includes letters from Pantheon Books
        - Publicity and reviews, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 48-50)
      - Gloria Mundi
        - Drafts, undated (Box 6, Folder 51-53)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 7, Folder 54-58)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 8, Folder 59-61)
        - Galley proofs, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 62-66)
        - Page proof, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 67)
        - Reviews, 1979-1980, undated (Box 9, Folder 68-69)
    - Non-Fiction
      - Eyes, Etc.
        - Drafts, 1976-1977, undated (Box 9, Folder 70-75)
        - Excerpt, 1977 July (Box 9, Folder 76)
        - Page proofs, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 77-80)
        - Book jacket and design, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 81)
        - Publicity and reviews, 1977-1978, undated (Box 10, Folder 82-84)
        - Empty envelopes, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 85)
      - Oysters of Locmariaquer
        - Research material, 1962-1964, undated (Box 10, Folder 86-87)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 11, Folder 88-95)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 12, Folder 96-102)
        - Inserts and discards, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 103)
        - Miscellaneous pages, 1964 June 18 (Box 13, Folder 104)
        - Galley proofs, 1964, undated
        - Advance proofs, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 105)
        - Plate proofs, 1964 March 30 (Box 13, Folder 106)
        - Page proofs, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 107-110)
        - Book jacket, [1964] (Box 13, Folder 111)
        - Illustrations, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 112)
        - Publicity and reviews, 1964-1973 (Box 13, Folder 113-116)
      - Rome and a Villa
        - Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 117-120)
        - Drafts, 1950, undated (Box 14, Folder 121-132)
        - Drafts, 1950-1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 133-140)
        - Index, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 141-142)
        - Uncorrected proof for advance readers, undated (Box 16, Folder 143-144)
        - Galley proof, undated
        - Printed versions (Doubleday edition), corrected, 1952, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 145-146)
        - Background materials for introduction ("Return to Rome") to 1975 edition, 1956-1974, undated (Box 16, Folder 147-148)
        - Drafts of "Return to Rome", [1974-1975] (Box 16, Folder 149-151)
        - Final proof (Pantheon edition), 1974 October (Box 17, Folder 152-154)
        - "Production Material", undated (Box 17, Folder 155)
        - Book jacket design (Pantheon edition), 1974 August 7
        - Galley proof of excerpt, 1974
        - Publicity and reviews, 1952-1983, undated (Box 17, Folder 156-158)
        - Introduction [to later edition?], undated (Box 17, Folder 159)
      - Tamrart: 13 Days in the Sahara
        - Draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 160)
        - Drafts, undated (Box 18, Folder 161-166)
        - Drafts and discards, undated (Box 18, Folder 167-168)
        - Excerpts, undated (Box 19, Folder 169-170)
        - Galley proof of excerpt, undated
    - Shorter Works
      - "America With a K," essay, draft and printed version, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - "Angel of Devastation," review, printed version, 1966 January 6
      - "The Art of Adventure," essay, undated (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - "Audubon: The Last Days of Nature," essay, drafts, proof, and printed version, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - "Bad Housekeeping," essay, notes, drafts, and printed version, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 174)
        Includes review, dated August 8, 1969
      - "The Ball," short story, drafts and printed versions, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 175-176)
      - "The Beauty", undated (Box 19, Folder 177)
      - "Berceuse," translation of poem by Saint-John Perse, undated (Box 19, Folder 178)
      - "Berenson's Last Years," review, galley proof and printed version, 1964 March 5
      - "Beside the Pyramid," essay, undated (Box 19, Folder 179-180)
      - "Brittany: Dragon Country," short story, drafts and printed version, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 181)
      - "The Cabinet of Dr. Kafka," review, 1938 February 2 (Box 19, Folder 182)
      - "Call Me Comrade," printed version, 1937 (Box 19, Folder 183)
      - "Cat's Cradle," short story, undated (Box 19, Folder 184)
      - "Centennial Note", [1975?] (Box 19, Folder 185)
      - "The Comfort of Rome," essay, [1954?] (Box 19, Folder 186)
      - "Commonweal or Common Woe?" review, printed version, 1964 July 9
      - "A Conversation With Eleanor Clark," interview, undated (Box 19, Folder 187)
      - "Conversations With Katherine Anne Porter... by Enrique Hank Lopoez," review, [1975?] (Box 19, Folder 188)
      - "Death of a Thinker," draft and printed version, undated (Box 19, Folder 189)
      - "Dorothea Tanning," tribute, undated (Box 19, Folder 190)
      - "Dostoyevsky's Huckleberry Finn," review, 1947 April 26 (Box 19, Folder 191)
      - "Dr. Heart," novella, undated (Box 19, Folder 192-193)
      - "Essay on Three Poems," printed version, 1934 March (Box 19, Folder 194)
      - "Existentialist Fiction," review, printed version, undated (Box 19, Folder 195)
      - "A Family in Magliana", undated (Box 19, Folder 196)
      - "The Fish," short story, undated (Box 19, Folder 197)
      - "Five O'Clock," short story, undated (Box 19, Folder 198)
      - "Friendships of a Lifetime", 1981 July 26
      - "The Garden," sketch, undated (Box 19, Folder 199)
      - "Gloop," short story, draft and printed version, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 200-201)
      - "Goodmorning, Shoemaker!" short story, undated (Box 20, Folder 202)
      - "A Happy Marriage," short story, draft and printed version, 1933, undated (Box 20, Folder 203)
      - "The Head in the Parlor," printed version, undated (Box 20, Folder 204)
      - "The Heart of the Afternoon," printed version, undated (Box 20, Folder 205)
      - "The Hill," short story, draft and printed version, 1938, undated (Box 20, Folder 206-207)
      - "Holiday," short story, undated (Box 20, Folder 208)
      - "Hurry, Hurry," short story, draft and printed versions, 1938, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 209)
      - "I Wonder What Mr. Santini Dreamed," reminiscence, draft and printed version, 1977, undated (Box 20, Folder 210-212)
      - "I'm Going Back to California," play, undated (Box 20, Folder 213)
      - "Infantilism and Steinbeck," review, printed version, 1947 March 29 (Box 20, Folder 214)
      - "Interview With Eleanor Clark and Robert Penn Warren," printed version, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 215)
      - "Journal From Puerto Rico," notes, drafts, and printed version, 1938, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 216-219)
      - "The Kingdom of Shadows," review, printed version, 1935 April 10 (Box 21, Folder 220)
      - "Landscape With Figures," short story, undated (Box 21, Folder 221)
      - "The Man For Her," short story, drafts and printed version, 1973 June (Box 21, Folder 222-223)
      - "The Man in a Cage," short story, undated (Box 21, Folder 224)
      - "The Man With a Book," short story, undated (Box 21, Folder 225)
      - "Monday We Change Our Clothes," play, draft and printed materials, 1974-1988, undated (Box 21, Folder 226-227)
      - "Monsieur Billybou," short story, drafts and discards, undated (Box 21, Folder 228-233)
      - "The Myth of Sainthood," review, printed version, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 234)
      - " Now That April's Here and Other Stories, by Morley Callaghan," review, printed version, 1936 October 21 (Box 22, Folder 235)
      - "Of Graves and Poets," essay, printed version, 1974 November (Box 22, Folder 236)
      - "One of the Few," review, printed version, 1935 October 9 (Box 22, Folder 237)
      - "Painter and Limner," reviews, printed version, 1935 May 8 (Box 22, Folder 238)
      - "The Personage," short story, undated (Box 22, Folder 239)
      - "Peter Marston," short story, undated (Box 22, Folder 240)
      - "The Pink Lady," review, printed version, 1940 January 15 (Box 22, Folder 241)
      - "Pinky," short story, undated (Box 22, Folder 242-243)
      - [Poems], drafts and printed versions, 1932-1934, undated (Box 22, Folder 244-246)
      - "Portrait in Blue," [excerpt?], drafts and printed version, 1965, undated (Box 22, Folder 247)
      - "Psychology and Symbols," review, printed version, 1947 April 26 (Box 22, Folder 248)
      - [Recipe], draft and printed version, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 249-250)
      - "Remembering Yaddo," essay, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 251)
      - "Responsibility," essay, printed version, undated (Box 22, Folder 252)
      - "Roman Journal 1974," [excerpt?] (Box 22, Folder 253)
      - "Roman Jubilee," essay, draft and printed version, 1975, undated (Box 22, Folder 254)
      - "Rome and a Writer," essay, printed version, 1975 January (Box 22, Folder 255)
      - "The Rowboat," short story, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 256)
      - "Rush Hour," short story, drafts and printed version, 1934, undated (Box 23, Folder 257)
      - "A Sahara Silhouette," essay, undated (Box 23, Folder 258)
      - "Scenario for a Cruise", undated (Box 23, Folder 259)
      - "The Sexual Woman's Guide to Brains, Babies, etc.," essay, undated (Box 23, Folder 260)
      - "Sidelight on a Gala," essay, [1983] (Box 23, Folder 261)
        Includes clippings dated January 25, 1983
      - "The Song of Roland", undated (Box 23, Folder 262-264)
      - "Sox and Garter," short story, undated (Box 23, Folder 265)
      - "Spanish Twilight," review, printed version, 1937 April 21 (Box 23, Folder 266)
      - "The Speaker Needs No Introduction," short story, undated (Box 23, Folder 267)
      - "Speaking of Books," [?], undated
      - [Speeches and readings], 1964-1984, undated (Box 23, Folder 268-270)
      - " The Star of Satan, by George Bernanos..." review, undated (Box 23, Folder 271)
      - "A Summer in Puerto Rico," journal, printed version, 1973 January (Box 23, Folder 272)
      - "The Taste of Nothing," review, printed version, 1936 September 9 (Box 24, Folder 273)
      - "The Temple", undated (Box 24, Folder 274)
      - "The Thief," play, [1973?] (Box 24, Folder 275-277)
      - "This is Not Home", undated (Box 24, Folder 278)
      - "Through War and Toothache," review, printed version, 1934 October 3 (Box 24, Folder 279)
      - "Trainboard", undated (Box 24, Folder 280)
      - "The Tree," short story, undated (Box 24, Folder 281)
      - [Trotsky translations], undated (Box 24, Folder 282)
      - "Twentieth Century Unlimited," essay, printed version, 1933 May (Box 24, Folder 283)
      - "The Untouchables," play, undated (Box 24, Folder 284-285)
      - "Vermont Flood" short story, undated (Box 24, Folder 286)
      - "The Virtuous Lady," short story, printed version, 1934 February (Box 24, Folder 287)
      - "The White Pony", undated (Box 24, Folder 288)
      - Untitled and unidentified drafts and fragments, 1933-1974, undated (Box 24, Folder 289-293)
  - Writings of Others
    - Hervé, Paul
      - Les Huitres, printed version, 1935 (Box 25, Folder 294)
    - Jarrell, Randall
      - The Animal Family, galley, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 295)
        Includes letter from Pantheon Books
    - Morris, William
      - A Journal of Travel in Iceland, photocopy, [1986?] (Box 25, Folder 296)
        Includes inscription from Saul Bellow
    - Osborn, Susan
      - [Interview], 1982 (Box 25, Folder 297)
        Includes letter, dated 21 October, 1982, from Osborn
    - Rice, Ethel P.
      - "Building the Good Ship U.S.A.", undated (Box 25, Folder 298-299)
      - [Diary], 1915 (Box 25, Folder 300)
      - [Poems], undated (Box 25, Folder 301)
      - [Shorter works], undated (Box 25, Folder 302-303)
    - Rice, John Pierrepont
      - [Poems], 1916-1940, undated (Box 25, Folder 304)
      - [Shorter works], 1919-1923, undated (Box 25, Folder 305)
    - Siegel, Sue Kreisman
      - [Interview], 1981 (Box 26, Folder 306)
        Includes letter, dated August 2, 1981, from Siegel
    - Stallworthy, Jon
      - [ Louis MacNeice ?], draft (pages 294-377), 1993 (Box 26, Folder 307)
        Includes letter, dated 15 March, 1993, from Stallworthy
    - Stedman, Edmund Clarence
      - "Centuria," poem, printed version, undated (Box 26, Folder 308)
    - Szogyi, Alex
      - "Lifting the Veil: Eleanor Clark's Linguistic Perceptions", 1979 (Box 26, Folder 309)
        Includes letter, dated December 3, 1979, from Szogyi
    - Warren, Robert Penn
      - [Untitled tribute to Leonid Berman], undated (Box 26, Folder 310)
    - Warren, Rosanna
      - "The Merry Minstrel News", 1964 June (Box 26, Folder 311)
- Correspondence, 1876-1988; Series II; 5; (12 boxes)
  Correspondence is organized into three subseries: General Correspondence, Third Party Correspondence, and Correspondence Relating to Writings.
  General Correspondence, housed in boxes 27-37 and arranged alphabetically by correspondent, consists chiefly of incoming letters from family, friends, writers, editors and publishers, and educational and cultural institutions. Larger correspondence files may be found for Clark's husband, Robert Penn Warren, her mother and children, Louis MacNeice, Katherine Anne Porter, and Muriel Rukeyser, among others. Other noteworthy correspondents include authors W.H. Auden, Saul Bellow, Hermann Broch, Albert Camus, John Cheever, Robert Fitzgerald, Elsa Morante, Eudora Welty, Glenway Wescott, and Thornton Wilder.
  General Correspondence also includes original outgoing letters from Clark to family members. Clark's letters to family members, including large files to her mother, Eleanor Phelps Clark, and daughter, Rosanna Warren, are foldered separately from incoming letters. Carbons of outgoing correspondence to others are documented in folder notes.
  Third Party Correspondence, housed in box 37 and arranged alphabetically by recipient, consists of all loose third party correspondence in the collection, and includes several letters between family members. Other third party letters probably came into Clark's possession as enclosures and, over time, were separated from the original letters.
  Files of correspondence relating to published works by Clark have been preserved in the subseries Correspondence Relating to Writings. These files, housed in box 38 and arranged alphabetically by title, consist chiefly of fan mail and letters from publishers. Letters from writers and correspondents found in the General Correspondence subseries are documented in folder notes. References ("see also" notes) are provided from General Correspondence where appropriate.
  - General Correspondence
    - "A" General, 1930-1978, undated (Box 27, Folder 312)
    - The American Review, 1974 January 4 (Box 27, Folder 313)
    - Antaeus, 1977, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 314)
    - Art & Antiques, 1984 January 3 (Box 27, Folder 315)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1968-1984 (Box 27, Folder 316)
    - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1972-1973, undated (Box 27, Folder 317)
      Includes printed ephemera
    - "B" General, 1937-1984 (Box 27, Folder 318)
    - Beard, Mary Ritter, 1933-1937 (Box 27, Folder 319)
    - Bellow, Saul, 1963-1984 (Box 27, Folder 320)
    - Blume, Peter, 1957-1985 (Box 27, Folder 321)
    - Broch, Hermann, 1940-1946 (Box 27, Folder 322)
    - Brooks, Cleanth, 1964-1980 (Box 27, Folder 323)
    - Broué, Pierre, 1978-1985 (Box 27, Folder 324)
      Includes outgoing correspondence
    - Brustein, Robert Sanford, 1972-1985 (Box 27, Folder 325)
    - Buchman, Gertrude, 1982-1983 (Box 27, Folder 326)
    - "C" General, 1929-1977 (Box 27, Folder 327-328)
    - Caldwell, Erksine, 1983-1984 (Box 27, Folder 329)
    - Camus, Albert, 1946-1947 (Box 27, Folder 330)
    - Capote, Truman, 1959-1965 (Box 27, Folder 331)
    - Carr, Virginia [Spencer?], 1973 (Box 27, Folder 332)
    - CBS Television Network, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 333)
    - Cheever, John, 1953-1969 (Box 27, Folder 334)
    - Child, Julia, 1973-1980 (Box 27, Folder 335)
    - Choate Rosemary Hall, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 336)
    - Clark, Eleanor Phelps (mother), 1929-1965 (Box 27, Folder 337-341)
    - Clark, Eleanor Phelps, 1929-1965 (Box 28, Folder 342-346)
    - Clark, Eleanor Phelps (outgoing), 1928-1966 (Box 28, Folder 347-354)
    - Clark, Frederick H. (father), 1936-1943 (Box 28, Folder 355)
    - Clemens, Cyril, 1975 March 27 (Box 28, Folder 356)
    - Columbia Forum, undated (Box 28, Folder 357)
    - Condé Nast Publications Inc., 1953 October 16 (Box 28, Folder 358)
    - Connecticut. State Board of Education, 1961 December 6 (Box 28, Folder 359)
    - Cowley, Malcolm, 1969-1984 (Box 28, Folder 360)
    - "D" General, 1941-1985 (Box 28, Folder 361)
    - Davison, Peter, 1974-1982 (Box 28, Folder 362)
    - Devlin, Denis, 1952-1959 (Box 28, Folder 363)
    - Dodds, Eric Robertson, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 364)
    - Donaldson, Scott, 1983-1985 (Box 28, Folder 365)
    - Doubleday and Company, Inc., 1962-1964 (Box 28, Folder 366-368)
      Includes drafts of "Hadrian's Villa"
    - "E" General, 1936-1985 (Box 28, Folder 369)
    - Eastman, Max, 1938 (Box 29, Folder 370)
    - Eberhart, Richard, 1937-1985 (Box 29, Folder 371)
    - Engle, Paul, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 372)
    - Esquire, 1970 December 9 (Box 29, Folder 373)